Register of the John Bell Condliffe Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Bell Condliffe Papers,
1918-1981
90015
Hoover Institution Archives
22 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope (9.7 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to various aspects of world economic conditions, especially international trade, the history of the development of world commerce, and the economic development of Australia, New Zealand and the entire Pacific basin region. Includes autobiographical writings.
Condliffe, J. B. (John Bell), 1891-1981
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1891, Dec. 23 Born, Melbourne, Australia
1913 B.A., Canterbury College
1914 M.A., University of Canterbury
1915 Lecturer in Economics, University of Canterbury
1914-1918 Served in the First World War with the New Zealand Division
1916 Married Olive Grace Mills
1919-1920 Gainville and Caius College, Cambridge
1920-1926 Professor of Economics, Canterbury College
1925 Attended the first conference of the Institute of Pacific Relations at Honolulu
1927 Received the degree of D.Sc. in Economics from the University of New Zealand
Author, Problems of the Pacific
1927-1931 Research Secretary, Institute of Pacific Relations, Hawaii
1930 Author, New Zealand in the Making
1930-1931 Visiting Professor of Economics, University of Michigan
1931 Author, Problems of Food and Population in the Pacific Area, and The Pacific Area in International Relations
1931-1937 Member, Economic Intelligence Service, League of Nations
1932 Author, China To-Day: Economic
1933 Author, World Economic Survey
1935 Author, A Short History of New Zealand, and War and Depression
1937-1939 Professor of Commerce, University of London
1938 Author, Markets and the Problem of Peaceful Change, and A Survey of International Research in Europe
1939 Recipient of Howland Memorial Prize, Yale University
Author, The Changing Structure of Economic Life
1940-1958 Professor of Economics, University of California, Berkeley
1940 Author, The Reconstruction of World Trade
1941 Author, Report Upon a Survey International House, University of California, Berkeley
1942 Received Honorary degree of LL.D., Occidental College
Author, Agenda For a Postwar World
1943 Author, The Economic Pattern of World Population
1943-1944 Research Associate, Institute of International Studies, Yale University
1943-1947 Associate Director, Division of Economics and History, Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
1944 Author, The Foreign Economic Policy of the United States, and The Common Interest in International Economic Organisation
1945 Naturalized citizen of the United States
Author, How Much Tariff Protection for Farm Products?, La Politica Economic Exterior De Estados Unidos, Exchange Stabilization, and World Economic Survey
1946 Author, Proposals For Consideration by an International Conference on Trade and Development
1947 Author, Obstacles to Multilateral Trading and The Foreign Loan Policy of the United States
1950 Recipient of Wendell Wilkie Prize
Author, The Commerce of Nations, The Economic Consequences of Scientific Research, and Point Four and the World Economy
1951 Author, Technological Progress and Economic Development and International Trade and Economic Nationalism
1953 Fellow, American Association for the Advancement of Science
1957 Received Honorary Litt.D. degree, University of New Zealand
1959-1960 Adviser, Indian National Council of Applied Economic Research, New Delhi
1959 Author, The Welfare State in New Zealand
1961-1967 Senior Economist, Stanford Research Institute
1964 Author, The Development of Australia
1965 Author, Foresight and Enterprise and From Adam Smith to Keynes -and After
1966 Author, The Balancing of International Payment: Money and Goods
1967 Author, The University and Technology
1969 Author, The Economic Outlook for New Zealand
1971 Author, Te Rangi Hiroa
1973 Erskine Fellow, University of Canterbury
1974 Author, Defunct Economists
1977 Gold Cross, Royal Order of Phoenix (Greece)
1981 Author, Reminiscences of the Institute of Pacific Relations
1981, Dec. 23 Died, Walnut Creek, California
Scope and Contents note
Speeches and writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to various aspects of world economic conditions, especially international trade, the history of the development of world commerce, and the economic development of Australia, New Zealand and the entire Pacific basin region. Includes autobiographical writings.
Australia--Economic conditions.; Australia.; Commerce.; Economic development.; Economists.; New Zealand--Economic conditions.; New Zealand.; Pacific area.; Pan-Pacific relations.
- Biographical File, 1949-1971
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketches, clippings, conference agenda, interview, leaflets, notes, telegram relating to the life of John Bell Condliffe, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Biographical sketches (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Conference agenda (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Interview (Summary of interview of John Condliffe by others) (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Leaflets (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Notes (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Telegram (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Correspondence, alphabetical, 1960-1971
  Significant correspondence of John Condliffe, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes a few letters neither from nor to John Condliffe, arranged alphabetically by Condliffe.
  - Bagnall, A. G., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Collins, C. W., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Dickson, Gordon, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Elmendorf, Armin, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Gormack, R. S., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Goodpaster, Andrew, 1959 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Hale, J. G., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Hames, J. R., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Hansen, Iris, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Hillman, Jimmye S., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Khourie, A., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Lovewell, P. J., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - North, Alfred, Sir, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Phillips, N. C., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Potamianos, K. S., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Simpson, John L., 1960 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Starke, June, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Turbott, G. G., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Whitfield, Earl, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 27)
- Correspondence, chronological, 1960-1971
  Less significant correspondence of John Condliffe, arranged chronologically by year. Includes a few letters neither from nor to John Condliffe.
  - 1960 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - 1971 (Box-folder 1: 33)
- Speeches and Writings, dated, 1919-1975
  Drafts, notes, printed copies, abstracts of speeches and writings by John Condliffe, reviews of his books, arranged chronologically. Also includes significant correspondence of John Condliffe relating to the writing and publication of his biography of Sir Peter Buck, along with a letter and an autobiographical chapter by Sir Peter Buck.
  - Educational Scheme, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - The Third Mediterranean in History, 1926 (Folder 1: 35)
  - "Some Questions on Pacific," speech, Institute of Pacific Relations, Kyoto, Japan, (German translation), Oct. 1929 (Folder 1: 36)
  - The Economic and Social Movements Underlying Antagonisms in the Pacific, July 1930 (Folder 1: 37)
  - Co-operative Research, 1931 (Folder 1: 38)
  - The Pacific Area in International Relations, March 1931 (Folder 1: 39)
  - China To-Day: Economic, 1932 (Folder 1: 40)
  - Report of the Gold Delegation of the Financial Committee, 1932 (Folder 1: 41)
  - War and Depression, 1935 (Folder 1: 42)
  - "The Evolution of Autarchy," Chapter VII, World Economic Survey, 1935-1936 (Folder 1: 43)
  - Review of Herman Kranold, The International Distribution of Raw Materials, Economica, 1938 (Folder 1: 44)
  - Review of G. C. Allen, Japan: The Hungry Guest, 1938 (Folder 1: 45)
  - Review of J. H. Clapham, An Economic History of Modern Britain: Machines and National Rivalries (1887-1914) with an Epilogue (1914-1929), Economica, 1938 (Folder 1: 46)
  - The Value of International Trade, 1938 (Folder 1: 47)
  - A Rural Experiment, bulletin, 1938 (Folder 1: 48)
  - "The Changing Structure of Economic Life," report, Journal of The International Chamber of Commerce, Aug. 1939 (Box 2: 1)
  - Peace Aims, discussion, The Eighth Fortune Round Table, Princeton, New Jersey, Feb. 14-16, 1941 (Folder 2: 2)
  - "Peace Out of War," address, American Section, International Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., 1942 (Folder 2: 3)
  - The Significance of International Trade, 1943 (Folder 2: 4)
  - "La Politica Economica Exterior de Estados Unidos," Jornadas, 1943 (Folder 2: 5)
  - The Economic Pattern of World Population, Jan. 1943 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Some Economic Aspects of Federalism in the British Commonwealth, 1944 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Hemisphere Development and the Common Man, a radio discussion, May 14, 1944 (Folder 2: 8)
  - "America's Foreign-Trade Policy," paper presented at the Conference of the Institute on Postwar Reconstruction at New York University, 1944 (Folder 2: 9)
  - "Exchange Stabilization," paper prepared for the Committee on International Economic Policy, 1945 (Folder 2: 10)
  - "Introduction," Robert L. Gulick, Jr., Imports: The Gain From Trade, 1946 (Folder 2: 11)
  - International Economic Collaboration, planning pamphlet, prepared by the National Planning Association Committee on International Policy, of which John Condliffe was a member, Feb. 1946 (Folder 2: 12)
  - "One Nankai Experiment," The China Magazine, June 1946 (Folder 2: 13)
  - "The Importance of World Commerce," The Free Trader, July-Aug. 1946 (Folder 2: 14)
  - "Proposals For Consideration by an International Conference on Trade and Employment," American Enterprise Association, Aug. 1946 (Folder 2: 15)
  - "The Keystone: Geneva," Survey Graphic, Sept. 1947 (Folder 2: 16)
  - "La Politica Statunitense Dei Prestiti Esteri," Economica Internazionale, 1948 (Folder 2: 17)
  - "The Foreign Loan Policy of the United States," Economica Internazionale, 1948 (Folder 2: 18)
  - "Know-How in Reconstruction and Development," lecture delivered at the Institute of Business and Economic Problems, 1948 (Folder 2: 19)
  - "Scholarship and Scholasticism," Liberty and Learning, 1950 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Point 4 and the World Economy, Headline Series, 1950 (Folder 2: 21)
  - "The Outlook For Trans-Pacific Trade," report prepared for the American President Lines, San Francisco, California, March 1950 (Folder 2: 22)
  - "The Unbalance of Our World," panel discussion at a Conference on International Cooperation for World Economic Development, University of California, Berkeley, March 16-17, 1950 (Folder 2: 23)
  - "The Economic Consequences of Scientific Research," The Joseph Fisher Lecture in Commerce given at the University of Adelaide, Sept. 8, 1950 (Folder 2: 24)
  - "International Trade and Economic Nationalism," International Conciliation, Dec. 1951 (Folder 2: 25)
  - The Power Struggle and the Middle East, pamphlet, Jan. 1952 (Box 3: 1)
  - "Supplement To Near East Report Country Studies,", July 1952 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Speech, reprinted from Papers and Proceedings, American Economic Review, May 1953 (Folder 3: 3)
  - "Recession in the United States," IPA Review, Oct.-Dec. 1953 (Folder 3: 4)
  - "Descent from the Summit," address before the Friends of Occidental College, Annandale Golf Club, Pasadena, Oct. 5, 1955 (Folder 3: 5)
  - "Summary: The Global Impact of the Middle East Crisis," lecture given at World Affairs Council of Northern California, San Francisco, Dec. 1, 1956 (Folder 3: 6)
  - "The Suez Canal," speech delivered at the World Affairs Council of Northern California, San Francisco, Dec. 1, 1956 (Folder 3: 7)
  - "New Zealand's Experiment in Economic Planning," The American Economic Review, Dec. 1957 (Folder 3: 8)
  - "The Fact of a University," address delivered at the University of Canterbury, Nov. 4, 1957 (Folder 3: 9)
  - "Population and Economic Development in New Zealand," Economic Development and Cultural Change, Jan. 1958 (Folder 3: 10)
  - The Welfare State in New Zealand, (Review only), 1959. (Folder 3: 11)
  - "Natural Resources and National Development," address to the Institute of Mining Engineers, U.S.A., ca. 1960 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Address, given at Stanford University to Professor Cottle's seminar, ca. 1960 (Folder 3: 13)
  - "Industry as a Vehicle of Education," draft for discussion at a Conference on Education and Economic Development, ca. 1960 (Folder 3: 14)
  - "The World Economy," preliminary text of paper for SRI Journal, Second Quarter, 1961 (Folder 3: 15)
  - "The Changing Structure of World Trade," prepared for presentation to the Industrial Conference, San Francisco, Sept. 11-15, 1961 (Folder 3: 16)
  - "The Attraction of Asia," presented to a faculty seminar at Mills College, Oct. 19, 1961 (Folder 3: 17)
  - "The European Economic Community," address given at the World Affairs Council of Northern California, Jan. 25, 1962 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Article in the California Monthly, March 1962 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Speech, at the American Association of Mining Engineers, Dallas, Texas, Feb 26, 1963 (Folder 3: 20)
  - "The Lessons of History," an internal document for SRI, Feb. 20, 1962 (Folder 3: 21)
  - "The Pattern of Trade in Food Stuffs," paper, (Includes revised version, Nov. 1962), April 1962 (Folder 3: 22)
  - "The Application of Research to Economic Policies in Developing Societies," paper prepared for presentation at the Association for Asian Studies, April 4, 1962 (Folder 3: 23)
  - "The Mineral Base of Industry,", June 1962 (Folder 3: 24)
  - "Some Comments on SRI Research Programs," draft prepared for SRI, ca., Aug. 3, 1962 (Folder 3: 25)
  - "Evolution of the British Empire to the Statute of Westminster," opening lecture given at the World Affairs Council of the Monterey Peninsula, Sept. 7, 1962 (Folder 3: 26)
  - "The Widening Gap," report prepared for SRI, Oct. 1962 (Folder 3: 27)
  - "Notes On Profits," paper, Oct. 9, 1962 (Folder 3: 28)
  - "Notes On Aerospace Industry," paper, Oct. 15, 1962 (Folder 3: 29)
  - "The Commonwealth and the Common Market," speech, World Affairs Council, San Francisco, Nov. 26, 1962 (Folder 3: 30)
  - "The Commonwealth and the Common Market," AICC Economic Review, Jan. 20, 1963 (Folder 3: 31)
  - "Christmas Address," University of California, Berkeley, Dec. 11, 1962 (Box 4: 1)
  - Seminar notes, Australian National University, April 18, 1963 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Seminar notes, Stanford University English Seminar, June 4, 1963 (Folder 4: 3)
  - "The U.S. Response To European Integration," speech, School of Law, University of California, June 28, 1963 (Folder 4: 4)
  - "Teamwork in Applied Research," The Pastoral Review and Graziers' Record, Sept. 18, 1963 (Folder 4: 5)
  - "Foreign Aid Re-examined," discussion at the World Affairs Council, Jan 9, 1964 (Folder 4: 6)
  - "The Political Economy of Science," paper presented at the Chit-Chat Club, April 13, 1964 (Folder 4: 7)
  - "The Balancing of International Payments," seminar discussion, Bank of America, May 28, 1964 (Folder 4: 8)
  - "The International Prospect," report, June 23, 1964 (Folder 4: 9)
  - From Adam Smith To Keynes - and After, Lakeside Talk, Bohemian Grove, July 30, 1964 (Folder 4: 10)
  - "So You're Going To Japan," speech, San Francisco State College, Aug. 26, 1964 (Folder 4: 11)
  - "Going To Sweden," speech, San Francisco State College, (includes a later revision written on the same day), Aug. 29, 1964 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Speech, Oct. 21, 1964 (Folder 4: 13)
  - "International Trends to '75," presentation delivered at the Long Range Planning Conference, Oct. 21-23, 1964 (Folder 4: 14)
  - "Mental Health in a Changing Community," paper presented at U.C. Medical Conference, San Francisco, (includes a handwritten note), Nov. 21-22, 1964 (Folder 4: 15)
  - "Foreign Direct Investment in the Pacific Area," memo for SRI project report, 1965 (Folder 4: 16)
  - "Pacific Trade and Development," confidential SRI series, Long Range Planning Report, 1965 (Folder 4: 17)
  - "The Economic Aspects of Conservation," Sierra Club Bulletin, June 1965 (Folder 4: 18)
  - "Space and the World Economy," (Abstract), Aug. 20, 1965 (Folder 4: 19)
  - "Sweden and Spain," speech, Orientation Conference, California State Colleges International Programs, Sept. 4, 1965 (Folder 4: 20)
  - "Closing Summary," Gold and the International Monetary Standard, 50th Anniversary Symposium, National Industrial Conference Board, Tarrytown, N.Y., Oct. 10, 1965 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Foresight And Enterprise, speech, Business Economic Section, Commonwealth Club, Oct. 26, 1965 (Folder 4: 22)
  - "Economic Theory and the World of Action," The IPA Review, Oct.-Dec. 1965 (Folder 4: 23)
  - "The Art of Problem-Solving," SRI memorandum, ca. 1965-1966 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Panel Presentation, Mental Health in a Changing Community, 1966 (Folder 4: 25)
  - "Higher Education Looks Abroad," paper presented to the Conference on the International Dimensions in the California State Colleges, Los Angeles, California, Jan. 28-29, 1966 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Speech, first drafts, April 11 and April 18, 1966 (Folder 4: 27)
  - "The Economic Outlook," SRI report, Sept. 19, 1966 (Folder 4: 28)
  - "The Pound Sterling: To Devalue Or Not To Devalue," speech, World Affairs Council Study Group, Nov. 17, 1966 (Folder 4: 29)
  - "The Guideline Economy," George Washington Law Review, Dec. 1966 (Folder 4: 30)
  - "Natural Resources and National Development," speech, American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers, Inc., Annual Meeting, Los Angeles, Feb. 19-23, 1967 (Box 5: 1)
  - "The University and Technology," address in the Hall of the University of Canterbury, (Includes printed extracts and typescript version), March 20, 1967 (Folder 5: 2)
  - The Beginnings of the W.E.A., 1968 (Folder 5: 3)
  - "Auri Sacra Fames," speech, Chit Chat Club, June 10, 1968 (Folder 5: 4)
  - "Business and Monetary Policy," paper presented at the U.C. Business School Alumni Conference, Nov. 6, 1968 (Folder 5: 5)
  - "The Economic Outlook For New Zealand," New Zealand Economic Papers, 1969 (Folder 5: 6)
  - "International Monetary Fund," Encyclopedia Britannica, 1969 (Folder 5: 7)
  - "Sterling Area," Encyclopedia Britannica, 1969 (Folder 5: 8)
  - "Free Trade," Encyclopedia Britannica, 1970 (Folder 5: 9)
  - "Money In Evolution," Arizona Review, Dec. 1970 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Prizegiving address, Te Aute College, Dec. 10, 1970 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Te Rangi Hiroa, Correspondence, 1971. (Folder 5: 12)
  - "The Parameters of Education," speech, Chit Chat Club, Oct. 11, 1971 (Folder 5: 13)
  - "The Control of Multinational Corporations," Economic Bulletin, Feb. 1973 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Address, Economic Society of Australia and New Zealand, Christchurch Branch, April 26, 1973 (Folder 5: 15)
  - Erskine Lectures, University of Canterbury, March 1973 (Folder 5: 16)
  - "Comments On Inflation," speech, Silverado Squatters, Bohemian Grove, July 19, 1973 (Folder 5: 17)
  - "Pacific Vistas,", 1975
    - Holograph
      - Unidentified (Folder 5: 18)
      - Chapter I (Folder 5: 19)
      - Chapter II (Folder 5: 20)
      - Chapter III (Folder 5: 21)
      - Chapter IV (Folder 5: 22)
      - Chapter V (Box 6: 1)
      - Chapter VI (Includes duplicate copy) (Folder 6: 2)
      - Chapter VII (Folder 6: 3)
      - Chapter VIII (Folder 6: 4)
      - Chapter IX (Folder 6: 5)
      - Chapter XI (Folder 6: 6)
      - Chapter XII (Folder 6: 7)
      - Chapter XIII (Folder 6: 8)
    - Typescript
      - Chapter I (Folder 6: 9)
      - Chapter II (Folder 6: 10)
      - Chapter III (Box 7: 1)
      - Chapter IV (Folder 7: 2)
      - Chapter V (Folder 7: 3)
      - Chapter VI (Folder 7: 4)
      - Chapter VII (Folder 7: 5)
      - Chapter VIII (Folder 7: 6)
      - Chapter X (Folder 7: 7)
      - Chapter XI (Folder 7: 8)
      - Chapter XII (Folder 7: 9)
      - Chapter XIII (Folder 7: 10)
      - Chapter XIV (Folder 7: 11)
      - Chapter XV (Folder 7: 12)
- Speeches and Writings, undated
  Drafts of undated, and mainly unpublished writings by John Condliffe, arranged numerically by chapters. Also includes some handwritten notes, typescript versions of papers, speech and report and a few printed copies of articles whose publication dates cannot be ascertained
  - Untitled, holograph (Box 8: 1)
  - Untitled, galley (Folder 8: 2)
  - Untitled paper, typescript (Folder 8: 3)
  - Speech, typescript (Folder 8: 4)
  - "Autobiography,"
    - Holograph
      - Unidentified (Folder 8: 5)
      - Chapter XIII (Folder 8: 6)
    - Typescript
      - Unidentified (Folder 8: 7)
      - Chapter I (Folder 8: 8)
      - Chapter II (Folder 8: 9)
      - Chapter III (Folder 8: 10)
      - Chapter IV (Folder 8: 11)
      - Chapter V (Folder 8: 12)
      - Chapter VI (Folder 8: 13)
      - Chapter VII (Folder 8: 14)
      - Chapter VIII (Folder 8: 15)
      - Chapter X (Folder 8: 16)
      - Chapter XI (Folder 8: 17)
      - Chapter XII (Folder 8: 18)
      - Chapter XIII (Box 9: 1)
      - Chapter XIV (Folder 9: 2)
      - Chapter XV (Folder 9: 3)
      - Chapter XVI (Folder 9: 4)
      - Chapter XVIII (Folder 9: 5)
  - "Economic Aspects of Security," holograph (Folder 9: 6)
  - "International Economic Tensions," typescript (Folder 9: 7)
  - "The Application of Research To Economic Policies In Developing Societies," both holograph and typescript versions (Folder 9: 8)
  - The Economic Aspects of Soviet-American Relations, printed copy (Folder 9: 9)
  - The New Order In China, printed copy (Folder 9: 10)
  - "The Teacher and his Influence," Liberty And Learning, printed copy (Folder 9: 11)
  - World Trade and Employment, printed copy (Folder 9: 12)
- Stanford Research Institute Office File, 1961-1971
  Drafts, published articles, conference papers, leaflets, SRI bulletins, sketch, memorandum are arranged chronologically. In some cases includes speeches and articles written by others.
  - 1961-1962 (Box 9: 13)
  - 1963-1967 (Folder 9: 14)
  - 1968-1971 (Folder 9: 15)
- Subject File, 1950-1966
  Lectures, clippings, travel accounts, reports, speeches, seminars, papers arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Australia (Box 10: 1)
  - Economics (Folder 10: 2)
  - India
    - Printed copy (Folder 10: 3)
    - Typescript (Folder 10: 4)
  - New Zealand (Folder 10: 5)
- Miscellaneous File, circa 1952-1971
  Annual reports, booklets, bulletins, clipping, conference program, speech by the President of the United States, printed articles, stickers, arranged chronologically.
  - General (Box 10: 6)
- Audio-Visual File
  General note
  See Photocard Catalog
- Incremental Materials (Box 11-23)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.